import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData: ExamData = {
    title: "Aircraft Oxygen Equipment",
    questions: [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "Without added oxygen the time of useful consciousness at 30 000 ft is approximately:",
            "options": [
                "twenty seconds",
                "eighty seconds",
                "one to two minutes",
                "six minutes"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "Without added oxygen the time of useful consciousness at 40 000 ft is approximately:",
            "options": [
                "twenty seconds",
                "three minutes",
                "eighty seconds",
                "six minutes"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "The maximum altitude without oxygen at which flying efficiency is not seriously impaired is:",
            "options": [
                "10 000 ft",
                "17 500 ft",
                "25 000 ft",
                "30 000 ft"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "In a pressure demand oxygen system:",
            "options": [
                "each member of the crew has a regulator",
                "each member of the crew has a continuous oxygen supply",
                "oxygen is supplied with a continuous pressure flow",
                "oxygen demand will cause the pressure to rise"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "In a continuous flow oxygen system, oxygen is supplied:",
            "options": [
                "only when the mask is plugged into the socket connection",
                "only on passenger inhalation through the mask",
                "only when the cabin altitude is above 18 000 ft",
                "only when the supply has been regulated by the pilot"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "In a diluter demand system, selection of emergency on this regulator will result in:",
            "options": [
                "air mix supplied at emergency pressure",
                "100% oxygen supply as called for by the user",
                "100% oxygen at positive pressure",
                "100% oxygen continuous flow at positive pressure"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "If the aircraft suffers a decompression passenger oxygen masks:",
            "options": [
                "are released by the passengers",
                "automatically drop to a half-hung (ready position)",
                "are handed out by the cabin staff",
                "must be removed from the life jacket storage"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Oxygen cylinders are normally charged to:",
            "options": [
                "1000 psi",
                "1200 psi",
                "1800 psi",
                "2000 psi"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "Rate of flow of oxygen is given in:",
            "options": [
                "litres/minute",
                "pounds/minute",
                "litres/second",
                "kilos/hour"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "The colour of American and European oxygen cylinders is:",
            "options": [
                "red",
                "blue",
                "green",
                "brown"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "Dangerous pressure rise in oxygen cylinders:",
            "options": [
                "is relieved by a thermostat",
                "is relieved by under pressurizing the bottle",
                "is relieved by a bursting disc",
                "is controlled by a thermal relief valve"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "To leak test an oxygen system use:",
            "options": [
                "fairy liquid and de-ionized water",
                "thin oil",
                "acid free soap and distilled water",
                "acid free soap and water"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "Lubrication of an oxygen component thread is by:",
            "options": [
                "soap water",
                "grease",
                "oil",
                "graphite"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "Satisfactory operation of the oxygen system is indicated by:",
            "options": [
                "flow indicators",
                "lack of anoxia",
                "aural reassurance",
                "pressure indicators"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "If the pressurization system fails and the cabin starts to climb, then at 14000 ft oxygen will be available to the passengers by:",
            "options": [
                "the stewardess who will hand out masks",
                "the passengers grabbing a mask from the overhead lockers",
                "portable oxygen bottles located in the seat backs",
                "masks automatically ejected to a half-hung position"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "When air is pressurized the % of oxygen:",
            "options": [
                "increases",
                "decreases",
                "remains the same",
                "nil"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "In an emergency chemically produced oxygen is supplied for a given period by:",
            "options": [
                "sodium chlorate, iron power, an electrical firing system and a filter",
                "potassium chlorate, iron powder, an electrical firing system and a filter",
                "sodium chlorate, iron powder which is chemically activated by air and then filtered",
                "sodium chlorate and an electrical firing system"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "Passenger oxygen masks will present:",
            "options": [
                "only when the cabin altitude reaches 14000",
                "only if selected by the crew",
                "only if selected by the cabin staff",
                "if selected manually / electrically / barometrically"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "The charged pressure of a portable oxygen cylinder is normally:",
            "options": [
                "500 psi",
                "1200 psi",
                "1800 psi",
                "3000 psi"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "With the control knob set to high, a 120 litre portable bottle will provide oxygen for a period of:",
            "options": [
                "60 mins",
                "30 mins",
                "12 mins",
                "3 mins"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 21,
            "question": "At what altitude will the diluter-demand oxygen regulator provide 100% pure oxygen:",
            "options": [
                "10 000 ft",
                "14 000 ft",
                "24 000 ft",
                "34 000 ft"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 22,
            "question": "A flow indicator fitted to an oxygen regulator indicates:",
            "options": [
                "that exactly the correct amount of oxygen is being used by the crew member",
                "that oxygen is flowing through the regulator",
                "that the crew member is correctly connected to the regulator",
                "that the system pressure reducing valve is supplying the correct pressure to the regulator"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 23,
            "question": "What is the approximate time of useful consciousness when hypoxia develops at the specified altitudes?\n\n20 000 ft / 30 000 ft",
            "options": [
                "2-3 min / 10-15 sec",
                "10 min / 2 min",
                "30 min / 90-60 secs",
                "40 min / 5 min"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 24,
            "question": "What is the effect on cabin temperature of a rapid de-compression at 30000 ft?",
            "options": [
                "Sudden and extreme drop",
                "Insignificant change over the first 2 minutes",
                "A gradual decrease to ambient over a period of about 10 minutes if the cabin heating ceases",
                "A gradual decrease to ambient temperature over a period of about 30 minutes if cabin heating continues"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 25,
            "question": "Susceptibility to hypoxia is increased by:",
            "options": [
                "heat",
                "noise",
                "smoking",
                "under-breathing"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 26,
            "question": "What is the approximate cabin altitude above which you must breath 100% oxygen if you are to maintain an alveolar partial pressure equal to that at sea level?",
            "options": [
                "26000 ft",
                "30000 ft",
                "34000 ft",
                "38000 ft"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        }
    ]
}